# Sufyan Saleem

Date of Birth: 4 Jan 1996 Marital Status: Single

Address: Åsgårdvegen 19, A2, 9016 Tromsø Website: <a href="https://sufyansaleem.netlify.app/">https://sufyansaleem.netlify.app/</a>
Email: sufyansalim94@gmail.com

# **OBJECTIVE**

I am a 25 years old Software Engineer who loves to play with different technologies. I am looking forward for a promising technical job where I will be subjected to new developmental areas with friendly environment for learning and emerging of my own personality with professional and in time work.

## WORK EXPERIENCE

Aido AS

Full Stack Developer

Remote, Norway

July 2021 - present

Working for this Development Agency. My main roles include developing Hybrid Mobile Applications, Web Applications etc in a 50%

position.

Linknbit Dec 2020 **MERN Stack Developer** 

Worked as part time project based remote MERN Stack developer.

Missog

Ecommerce StoreUnder Development

React, Nodejs, Express, MongoDB, Digital Ocean

**Decklaration** 

Jun 2020 – Aug 2020

**MERN Stack Engineer** 

Working for NY based design Agency. My main roles include developing Web Applications, Backend and Hybrid Mobile

Applications.

Remote

Remote

Mertium

Similar to Bloomberg.

I developed the frontend based on template HTML, CSS, Less, React

**Medtigo** 

Provides services for hospitals

I developed the Backend in Nodejs, Express, MSQL, Sequelize, Node mailer, Security for XSS and SQL Injection

Linknbit

Software Engineer

Jan 2019 – May 2020 Working for Software Development and IT Solutions Agency. My main roles include developing Web Applications and Hybrid

Mobile Applications.

Islamabad, Pakistan

#### Kyla App

- It is a Mobile App to know your laws
- Recommended actions
- Contact lawyer with location and details
- Paid and Unpaid Feature

#### Global Aviation System

• For Central African Republic

Developed the backend in NodeJS, Express, MongoDB, Node mailer, Geolocation, Security for XSS and NOSQL Injection

I am worked on parts of backend Node JS, Express, Sequelize CLI, PassportJS & Azure SQL, Swagger

#### **Dynasty Unleashed Models**

- Modeling agency App for Fashion designers and marketers
- Users can register, create profile, add people and hire models at will

Developed part of Front-End in React/React-Native & part of Deployment to Firebase & Google Play

#### Dokkani.co

- Ecommerce Mobile App.
- User can register, select products, add products to cart.
- User add products to wish list and checkout.
- Project was abandoned on last stage due to funds not provided and outsourced to someone else.
- My Version

React/React-Native, Expo, Redux, Node JS, Rest API, Word Press API, Woo Commerce API, Native Base

#### Yogurt App

 Step-by-step guide to home crafted authentic Yogurt and Kefir. Take the directions on your phone. Make Yogurt and Kefir at home and communicate. Developed part of Front-End in React/React-Native, Expo, Native Base

#### **SmartsAid**

NGO App for refuges

React/React-Native, Expo, Redux, Firebase, Rest API, React Native Elements

2018 - FYP

Currency Recognition & Conversion

 Developed an app where users can scan currency note and it will tell which currency it is and how much is it and show the exchange rate in USD. Android, Java, Open CV, Rest API, MATLAB

2014 - 2018

Content Management Systems

Java, C#, MSSQL

Java

Gym - Point of Sale

PHP, HTML, CSS, MySQL

2010

RuneScape RPG

 Created bot script for the game called RuneScape. The bot played the game for you.

Note: For more projects checkout the website mentioned in the header of the resume.

# **EDUCATION**

# Master of Science in Computer Science

UiT, Tromsø (Aug 2020 – present)

## Internet of things and AI Specialist Course

PIAIC, Islamabad (2019), Only First Quadrant

### BS in Software Engineering, cgpa 2.78

Institute of Managements Sciences, Peshawar (2014 – 2018)

### F.Sc - Pre-Engineering, grade B

ICMS College System Peshawar (2012 – 2014)

### 10 Matric, grade A

Racines School System, Peshawar (2010 – 2012)

# **SPECIALITY AND KNOWLEDGE**

### **Specialities**

Mobile/Hybrid App Developer Web Developer

### **Social Links**







### Knowledge

React/React-Native, Redux, Expo Vanilla JS, Node JS, Express Mongoose, Sequelize Firebase, Mongo DB, MySQL, PostgreSQL HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Material UI Git, Heroku, Netlify, Digital Ocean, Amazon Rest, GraphQL, MVC

Bash, Rust

Word press, Android Studio, Adobe PS

# **LANGUAGES AND HOBBIES**

#### Languages

English Urdu Pashto

#### **Hobbies**

Programming, Music, Movies, Video Games, Reading, Hiking, Bodybuilding, Boxing